Amit Penmetcha

New York, NY

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Amit-Penmetcha/9bfb23fa666a6200

Software Engineer

Software Engineer with a great deal of experience in software development on web based applications and large scale systems. Experience with systems engineering and working with a customer to refine requirements. Certified Scrum Master with experience in Agile methodologies. Great team player who also likes to take charge and works hard to deliver clean and robust software and to continuously improve software development processes used by both the team and program.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Forcepoint - Herndon, VA July 2017 to Present

- Developer for a Cross Domain Solution (CDS) team, designing and developing products to aid secure transfer of classified and sensitive information between two security domains.
- Leading effort to develop capability to reconfigure system without any downtime.
- Developed web applications and backend processes primarily in Java/Javascript to support authentication and authorization of users, process uploaded content, and manage/configure other processes. Used Spring Framework and MySQL/Postgres DBs. Developed SELinux policy for securing applications.
- Developed Python and bash based automation tests to increase efficiency in testing and increase coverage.
- Regularly participate in code reviews and work with others on designing architectural changes and feature enhancements.
- Worked in a primarily Linux environment, developing software for a product that runs on Security Enhanced RHEL 6 and 8. Working in both SVN and Git repositories.

Software Engineer Level 4

Leidos - Ashburn, VA June 2012 to July 2017

Automated Flight Service Station (AFSS)

- Scrum Master and team lead for 8 person team.
- Developed web application for pilots with flight planning, weather briefing, and route planning capabilities.
- Developed code in Java, Javascript, and JSP using the Spring Framework. Also developed REST/SOAP based web services for vendors to utilize AFSS's flight services, such as flight planning and weather briefings.
- Analyzed and improved performance of website and web services by 30% for key functions.
- · Led team in creating automated regression test scripts for both the website and web services in Perl.
- Reduced testing effort by 50%.
- Used Agile Scrum methodology for developing software.

- Prior to becoming team lead, was recognized for taking charge, leading planning, designing, and implementation of various products. Served as backup Scrum Master on numerous occasions. This led to being promoted to team lead/Scrum Master.
- Won several performance excellence awards for contributions to the project.

Systems Engineer Level 2

Lockheed Martin - Rockville, MD April 2010 to April 2012

System Wide Information Management (SWIM)

- Worked with FAA customers to develop web service interface between company's air traffic control software and other air traffic control services.
- Developed XML schemas and Web Service Description Documents, defining the web service interface to be provided to other vendors.
- Worked with client to develop System Requirements Documents (SRDs). Supported Air Traffic
- Control program in England, developing SRDs for high priority functionality.
- Developed strong communication and technical skills and the ability to analyze an entire system and engineer solutions.

Software Engineer Level 2

Lockheed Martin - Rockville, MD June 2009 to April 2010

En Route Automation Modernization (ERAM)

- Developed functionality related to providing real time flight information for all enroute flights entering, within, and exiting the United States. Troubleshot and delivered software fixes for issues that occurred in operations.
- Coordinated and worked with System/Software Architects within Lockheed and FAA personnel to properly define the desired behavior.
- Developed code in Ada on Unix based text editors. Gained familiarity with software development practices, such as version control, coding conventions, inspecting software, design reviews, and testing strategies.
- Worked on regression testing, inspections, and other functions to insure successful delivery.
- Helped improve and maintain a wiki for the team that documented the architecture and functionality of the software in order to serve as a training resource for new team members.

Education

Masters of Science in Systems Engineering

Johns Hopkins University - Baltimore, MD December 2014

Masters of Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Cornell University - Ithaca, NY May 2009

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Cornell University - Ithaca, NY

May 2008

Skills

- Agile/Scrum methodology
- Experience with MySQL and Postgres
- Familiar with tools such as Jenkins, JIRA,
- Web application development BitBucket, and Crucible
- Spring Framework
- Strong technical skills with an ability to learn
- REST/SOAP Web Services quickly and take charge.
- Experience with Linux
- SELinux
- Windows
- Java
- JavaScript
- Python
- Shell
- Git
- SVN
- APIs
- XML
- JSON
- Maven
- JUnit
- Tomcat
- CI/CD
- Shell Scripting
- Waterfall
- SDLC
- jQuery
- JDBC

Certifications and Licenses

Certified Scrum Master